(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Ready?
Go!
Here we go!
Ready?
Go!
Here we go!
Ready? Go!
ミュージック・アワー / 宝鐘マリン
Music Hour / Houshou Marine
君たち、生誕祭に来てくれてありがとう！
You guys, thank you for coming to my birthday celebration!
いっぱい趣味を詰め込んだので
I've packed in so many of my hobbies,
最後までいっぱい聴いていってくださいね！
so please listen to them all until the very end!
盛り上げてください！
Get hyped!
お願いします！
Please!
この番組ではみんなのリクエストをお待ちしています
On this program, we are waiting for everyone's requests
素敵な恋のエピソードと一緒にダイヤルをして
Dial in along with a wonderful love episode
ここでおハガキを一通
Here is a postcard,
ラジオネーム“恋するウサギちゃん”
radio name "In Love Rabbit-chan"
「なぜ人を好きになると
“Why does it become
こんなに苦しいのでしょう？」
so painful when you fall in love with someone?”
それは心が君のこと
That's because your heart
急かして蹴飛ばしているからで
is rushing and kicking you
シンプルな頭で聞けばいいのさ
Just listen with a simple mind,
Let’s get your love!
君が胸を焦がすから
Because your heart is burning,
夏が熱を帯びてく
summer is taking on the heat
そして僕は渚へと
And I'll deliver a number
誘うナンバーを届けてあげる
to the shore that invites you
淡い恋の端っこを
If you never let go
決して離さなければ
of the edge of a faint love
この夏は例年より
This summer, noisier days
騒がしい日が
than usual...
続くはずさ
...should continue
Hey!
もしも世界中で...
If everywhere in the world...
強い人にはなれそうにもない
I don't think I can be a strong person.
揺れてる君でいいよ
It's okay to be your wavering self.
君が夢を願うから
Because you're wishing for a dream,
ミュージシャンも張り切って
The musicians are getting fired up too.
まだ露も泣き顔に
Even with dew on a tearful face,
新しいナンバー溢れていくよ
New numbers are starting to overflow.
淡い恋の端っこを
If you don't let go...
決して離さなければ
...of the edge of a faint love...
この夏は例年よりそう
...then this summer will surely be...
涼しい日が続くはずさ
...followed by cooler days than usual.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！君たち！盛り上がってくれてますかー？
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! You guys! Are you having a good time?
バイブス、上がってますかー？
Are your vibes up?
まだまだ続くし、重大発表もあるので、最後までぶち上げて下さいねー！
There's still more to come, and I have a major announcement, so keep it hyped up until the end!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
はーい！
Haa-i!
というわけで、皆様！
So, everyone!
どうも、どうも！
Hello, hello!
船長の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to Captain's birthday live!
はい、今日はですね、宝鐘マリン...
Yes, today...
ハッシュタグ 宝鐘マリン生誕祭2021でいっぱい呟いてください。
...please tweet a lot with the hashtag #HoushouMarineBirthday2021.
いっぱいスクショとかしてくださいね。
Take lots of screenshots too.
感想待ってわし。
I'm waiting for your thoughts-washi.
今日ですね、この後はもう...
Today, after this...
怒涛の超超ゲストメドレー！
...is the non-stop super-super guest medley!
いっぱいゲストが来ますので、
Since lots of guests are coming,
どんな曲を誰とどの曲をやるのか、ちょっとわくわくしながら見ていてくださいね。
...please look forward to which songs I'll be performing with whom.
ぜひぜひいっぱいどしどし呟いてください。
Please tweet away as much as you can.
ふぅ！誕生日だ！イエーイ！
Whew! It's my birthday! Yay!
それじゃ、ゲストパートいきますよ。
Alright, moving on to the guest part.
出航！イエーイ！
Set sail! Yay!
Happiness World / 宝鐘マリン・白上フブキ
Happiness World / Houshou Marine & Shirakami Fubuki
One, two, three, hey! Yay!
ねえそこのお嬢さん ここはもうすぐパラダイス
Hey there, young lady, this place is about to be paradise.
不満げな顔しちゃダメだよ ダメダメ
Don't make a dissatisfied face, no no.
スマイルがパスポート それがあればもう安泰
A smile is your passport; with that, you're all set.
楽しんでいこうよ パラダイダイ ほらじゃあ
Let's have fun, para-die-die, look, now...
勇気出して
...take courage.
One, two, step, yay!
今までの常識とは
From the common sense until now...
明らかに違う世界
...it's clearly a different world.
フルブーストで楽しもうよ
Let's enjoy it with full boost!
今だけチャンスだ 夢を掴もう
Now is the only chance, let's grab the dream!
明日から紙吹雪 ビーバ！
Confetti from tomorrow, viva!
想像もしなかった 出来事がきっと
Events you never imagined...
待ってるさ
...are surely waiting for you.
シンガソングで 心踊らせ
With a sing-a-song, make your heart dance.
ポジティブに さあ舵いっぱい
Stay positive, now, full rudder!
気持ち晴ればわたる その瞬間
The moment your feelings clear up...
全速前進！
...full speed ahead!
いつだって一人じゃない
You're never alone.
私たちと一緒に 最高...
Together with us, the best...
Very Happy な人生を！ Yeah!
A very happy life! Yeah!
あー、むいて、ねむい。ずっとベッド出たくない。
Ah, I'm peeling and sleepy. I never want to leave my bed.
ねむ、無駄じゃない？今日は休みなんです。すいまぱい！
Sleepy... isn't it a waste? Today is my day off. Sorry-pi!
セッション、ときはセッション。何かやりたいことやってみよう！
Session, when it's a session... Let's try doing something we want to do!
セッション、としてこう。君の内に秘めた欲望、オー！
Let's keep it a session. The desire hidden within you, oh!
思い切り！
With all our might!
宝鐘マリン 生誕祭ライブ
重大発表あり！ゲスト多数！
Houshou Marine Birthday Live
Major announcement! Many guests!
宝鐘マリン生誕祭ライブ
HOUSHOU MARINE BIRTHDAY LIVE 2021
Houshou Marine Birthday Live
重大発表あり！ゲスト多数！
Major announcement! Many guests!
Ahoy!! 宝鐘海賊団船長の、宝鐘マリンです！
Ahoy!! I'm the Captain of the Houshou Pirates, Houshou Marine!
出航ー！
Set sail!
ヨーソロー！
Steady as she goes!
全速前進！
Full speed ahead!
面舵いっぱい！
Hard-a-starboard!
野郎どもー！準備はいいかー！？
You scallywags! Are you ready?!
アイアイサ〜！
Aye Aye Sir!
キミたち、今日は私のために集まってくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for gathering here for me today!
最高の１日にしようね！
Let's make this the best day ever!
それじゃあ、いくよー！
Alright, here we go!
１・２・３・４！
1, 2, 3, 4!
Ahoy!!
水平線の向こう側　何が待っているのかな
I wonder what's waiting beyond the horizon
ワクワクが止まらない　最高の仲間たちと
I can't stop the excitement with the best crew
嵐も越えて行こう　舵を取れ　帆を張れ
Let's cross the storms too, take the helm, set the sails
目指すはお宝さ　ヨーソロー！
Our goal is the treasure, steady as she goes!
Ahoy!!
キミと一緒にいたいから　宝物を探しに
Because I want to be with you, off to find the treasure
キラキラ輝いて　眩しい世界へ
Sparkling and shining, towards a dazzling world
波風立てちゃって　ごめんあそばせ
Pardon me for stirring up a few waves
私が一番の　海賊船長！
I am the number one pirate captain!
Ahoy!!
パンパカパーン！　パンパンパン　パンパカパーン！
Pan-paka-paan! Pan-pan-pan Pan-paka-paan!
お宝どこかな？　キミの胸の中？
Where's the treasure? Inside your chest?
それともあっち？　こっち？　そっちかな？
Or is it there? Over here? Maybe over there?
「えーい、全部奪っちゃうぞー！」
"Hey, I'm gonna take it all!"
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
Ahoy!! We are the Houshou Pirates☆
世界一の　お宝探そう
Let's search for the world's greatest treasure
ワクワクが止まらない　夢の航海へ
Can't stop the excitement on this dream voyage
キミのハートに　宝鐘マリン！
Into your heart, Houshou Marine!
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
Ahoy!! We are the Houshou Pirates☆
笑顔の花　咲かせましょう
Let's make the flowers of smiles bloom
一生ついてきてね　約束だよ！
Follow me for the rest of your life, that's a promise!
出航ー！
Set sail!
...の切れ間に
...through the breaks in the clouds.
見知らぬ空　覗かせる
A strange sky peeks through.
あの日から繋がった未来に
To the future that has been connected since that day.
僕らまだ足取りも覚束ないけど
Our steps are still unsteady, but...
強い風を受け
Facing the strong wind,
止まることなく
without stopping,
ただひたむきに歩き続けたい
I just want to keep walking single-mindedly.
信じたこの道を
On this path I believe in.
Wow wow...
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
はい！というわけで、マリンとぐらで「空色デイズ」歌わせていただきましたー！
Alright! So, Marine and Gura just sang "Sorairo Days"!
Yeah!
Thank you Gura!
Thank you!
ああ、ぐらー！かわいいよー！
Ah, Gura! You're so cute!
暑いね！夏だね！
It's hot! It's summer!
ふぅー。
(Exhales)
よし！じゃあ、ちょっと... ぐら、日本語、頑張ってくれるかな？
Alright! So, Gura... could you try your best with Japanese for a bit?
Yes! 頑張ります！
Yes! I'll do my best!
おー、いい声だ。
Oh, what a nice voice.
じゃあ、自己紹介、お願いします！
Then, please introduce yourself!
はい！
Yes!
えっと...
Um...
ホロライブEnglishの、がうる・ぐらです！
I am Gawr Gura from Hololive English!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
イエーイ！ぐらちゃん、よろしくお願いします！
Yay! Nice to meet you too, Gura-chan!
わあ、いい発音だね。
Wow, your pronunciation is great.
よし。じゃあ、ぐら、マリンの、印象を、教えてくれるかな？
Okay. Then Gura, can you tell me your impression of Marine?
印象？
Impression?
そうそう、Marine impression.
That's right, Marine impression.
おー、えーと...
Oh, um...
マリン先輩は...
Marine-senpai is...
セクシーで...
Sexy, and...
あー、ベリー、ベリー...
Ah, very, very...
セクシー...
Sexy...
です！
she is!
セクシー！？
Sexy!?
おー、セクシー！
Oh, sexy!
センキュー、センキュー！
Thank you, thank you!
よくわかってるね、ぐらちゃんは！
You really get it, Gura-chan!
Yeah!
うれしいなー、もう。
I'm so happy.
じゃあ、もう一つ。
One more thing.
ぐら、マリンの、こと、好き？
Gura, do you like Marine?
あー...
Ah...
大好きです！
I love you!
大好きー！？
You love me!?
やったー！
Yay!
ぐらちゃん、大好きって言ってくれた！
Gura-chan said she loves me!
よしよしよし。
Good, good, good.
じゃあ、ぐら。次は、一緒に、重大発表を、見てくれるかな？
Alright, Gura. Next, will you watch the important announcement with me?
重大発表？
Important announcement?
そうそう。Important announcement.
Yes, yes. Important announcement.
Okay!
よし。じゃあ、VTR、どうぞ！
Alright. Then, here's the VTR!
Ahoy!! 宝鐘海賊団、船長の宝鐘マリンです！
Ahoy!! I'm the captain of the Houshou Pirates, Houshou Marine!
Ahoy!!
全速前進！
Full speed ahead!
ヨーソロー！
Yousoro!
出航だー！ 面舵いっぱい！
Setting sail! Hard-a-starboard!
荒波越えて お宝探し
Crossing the rough waves, searching for treasure
（水平線の彼方へ！）
(To the far side of the horizon!)
金銀財宝 略奪だー！
Gold, silver, and jewels... plunder it all!
（そこのけそこのけ！）
(Get out of the way, get out of the way!)
いざ、進め！ どこまでも！
Now, advance! No matter how far!
（我ら宝鐘海賊団！）
(We are the Houshou Pirates!)
情熱の嵐 巻き起こせ！
Kicking up a storm of passion!
はい！ ということで！
All right! And so!
続いてのゲストは、ホロライブEnglishの皆さんです！
The next guests are the members of Hololive English!
Happy Birthday, Marine-senpai!
わー！ ありがとう！
Wow! Thank you!
まさかENのみんなとこの曲を歌えるなんて思わなかった！
I never thought I'd get to sing this song with everyone from EN!
みんな、日本まで来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming all the way to Japan!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
水着、めちゃくちゃ似合ってるよ！ かわいい！
The swimsuits look great on you! So cute!
You look great too, Marine-senpai!
えー！ 嬉しい！
Oh! I'm so happy!
日本語もすごく上手だったよ！ 練習したの？
Your Japanese was really good too! Did you practice?
We practiced a lot for you!
最高だね！ 感動しちゃう！
That's amazing! I'm so moved!
ぐらちゃん、イナちゃん、カリちゃん、キアラちゃん、アメちゃん！
Gura-chan, Ina-chan, Calli-chan, Kiara-chan, Ame-chan!
みんなに会えて本当に嬉しいよ！
I'm so truly happy to meet you all!
それじゃあ、ホロライブEnglishのみんなでした！ ありがとう！
Well then, that was everyone from Hololive English! Thank you!
Bye-bye! Happy Birthday!
バイバイー！
Bye-bye!
はい！ ということでね！
Yes! And so!
いやー、ENのみんな、可愛かったですね！
Man, the EN members were so cute!
水着姿で一緒に踊れて、船長はもう感無量です！
Being able to dance together in swimsuits, I'm just overwhelmed with emotion!
さてさて、生誕祭ライブ、まだまだ盛り上がっていきますよ！
Now then, the birthday live is going to keep heating up!
続いてのゲストはこの方々です！ どうぞ！
The next guests are these people! Here they are!
君たち！生誕祭ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Hey everyone! Thanks for coming to my birthday live!
いっぱい趣味を詰め込んだので、
I've packed this with so many of my hobbies,
最後までいっぱい聴いてってくださいね。盛り上げてください！
so please enjoy it until the end! Please get excited!
この番組ではみんなのリクエストをお待ちしています
On this program, we are waiting for everyone's requests.
素敵な恋のエピソードと一緒にダイヤルをして
Dial in along with your wonderful love episodes.
ここでお葉書を一通 ラジオネーム恋するウサギちゃん
Here is a postcard. Radio name: Lovesick Bunny-chan.
「なぜ人を好きになるとこんなにも苦しいのでしょう」
"Why does falling in love have to be so painful?"
それは心が君のこと 急かして蹴飛ばしているから
That's because your heart is rushing and kicking you forward.
シンプルな頭で聞けばいいのさ プレジャー・チャウ
You just need to listen with a simple mind. Pleasure...
君が胸を焦がすから 夏が熱を帯びてく
Because you are burning with passion, the summer gains heat.
そして僕は渚へと 誘うナンバー届けてあげる
And I will deliver a track that invites you to the shore.
淡い恋の端っこを 決して放さなければ
If you never let go of the edge of that faint love...
この夏は例年より 騒がしい日が続くはずさ
This summer is sure to be noisier than usual!
少しは参考になったかな ラジオネーム恋するウサギちゃん
Was that a bit helpful, Lovesick Bunny-chan?
そして世界中で叶わぬ恋にお悩みの方
And to those all over the world worrying about unrequited love...
多分心は迷っていて 壊れかけたピアノみたいだ
Your heart is probably lost, like a broken piano.
ルールがいつまでも 曖昧なままイッツ・ゲーム・オーバー
With the rules remaining vague forever, it's game over.
君が夢を願うから 今も夢は夢のまま
Because you are wishing for a dream, even now the dream remains a dream.
大好きだから踏み出せない 大好きだから臆病になる
Because I love you so much, I can't take a step; because I love you so much, I become a coward.
淡い恋の真ん中を 泳ぎきって見せてよ
Show me how you can swim right through the middle of that faint love.
可愛すぎるハートを 見守ってる ミュージック・アワー
Music Hour is watching over your all-too-cute heart.
強い人には なれそうにもない 揺れてる君でいいよ
You don't need to become a strong person. It's fine just being your wavering self.
君が夢を願うから ミュージシャンも張り切って
Because you are wishing for a dream, the musicians are also fired up.
また今年も渚には 新しい名前溢れていくよ
This year too, the shore will be overflowing with new names.
淡い恋の端っこを 決して放さなければ
If you never let go of the edge of that faint love...
この夏は例年より 騒がしい日が続くはずさ
This summer is sure to be noisier than usual!
君たち！盛り上がってくれてますかー！
Everyone! Are you getting excited?!
バイブス上がってますかー！
Are your vibes up?!
まだまだ続くし、重大発表もあるので最後までぶち上げてくださいね！
It's still continuing, and there are major announcements, so please keep the hype going until the end!
はい！
Yes!
っていうことで、ラヴいひと時を...
So, for a lovely moment...
はい！っていうことで皆様、どうもどうも
Hi! So everyone, thank you, thank you
船長の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
for coming to the Captain's birthday live!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はい今日はですね、宝鐘マリン
Yes, today, Houshou Marine,
#宝鐘マリン生誕祭2021でいっぱい呟いてください。
please tweet a lot with #HoushouMarineBirthday2021.
いっぱいスクショとかしてくださいね。感想待ってます。
Please take lots of screenshots too. I'm waiting for your impressions.
今日はですね、この後はもう怒涛の
Today, after this, we have an overwhelming
超超ゲストメドレー！いっぱいゲストが来ますので、
super-super guest medley! Many guests will come,
もうどんな曲を誰とどの曲をやるのかちょっとワクワクしながら見ていてくださいね。
so please look forward to who will perform what song together while you watch.
ぜひぜひいっぱいどしどし呟いてください。
Please, please, tweet a lot, more and more.
うわ！誕生日だ！イェーイ！
Whoa! It's my birthday! Yay!
それじゃあゲストパートいきますよ。
Well then, let's go to the guest part.
出航！イェーイ！
Setting sail! Yay!
Happiness World
宝鐘マリン・白上フブキ
Houshou Marine Birthday 3D Live
Happiness World
Houshou Marine & Shirakami Fubuki
Houshou Marine Birthday 3D Live
1, 2, 3, Hey, Yay!
ねえそこのお嬢様 ここはパラダイスだよ
Hey there, young lady. This is paradise.
不満げな顔しちゃダメだよダメダメ
Don't make a dissatisfied face. No, no.
スマイルがパスポート それがあれば満点
A smile is your passport. With that, it's perfect.
楽しんでいこうよ パラダイスタイム
Let's have some fun. It's paradise time.
鼻歌歌っちゃう 勇気出して
I'll start humming. Gather your courage.
1, 2 step yay
今までの景色とは 明らかに違う世界
A world clearly different from the scenery until now.
フルブーストで 楽しもうよ
Let's enjoy it with a full boost.
イマダ ゲッタチャンスだ 夢を掴もう
Now's the time! Get a chance and grab your dream.
明日から 紙吹雪フィーバー
Starting tomorrow, it's confetti fever.
想像したことない出来事が きっと待ってるさ
Events you've never imagined are surely waiting for you.
シングアソングで 心躍らせ
Sing a song and make your heart dance.
ポジティブに さあ 帆を上げ いっぱい
Stay positive! Now, raise the sails high.
気持ち晴れ渡るその瞬間 全速前進だ
The moment your feelings clear up, go full speed ahead.
いつだって 1人じゃない
You're never alone.
私たちと一緒に 最高にハッピーな人生を yay!
Live a most happy life together with us. Yay!
雨降ってイタい 眠い ずっとベッド 出たくない
It's raining and it hurts. I'm sleepy. I don't want to leave my bed.
ねむたじゃない 今日は休み なんでSleep my time
It's not just sleepiness. Today is a day off, so why sleep my time away?
そういう時はそう 何かやりたいことやってみよう
In times like that, yes, let's try doing something you want to do.
紹介していこう 君の内に秘める野望
Let's introduce them—the ambitions hidden inside you.
思い切り 思い切り 声を出して
Give it your all, give it your all, shout it out!
3, 2, 1 yay!
恥ずかしい気持ちとは 今すぐにバイバイさ
Say goodbye to those feelings of embarrassment right now.
エンジン全開 はじけようよ
Full engine throttle! Let's burst forth.
進めよ イマイメだ 立ち止まらずに
Move forward! It's the 'now' dream, don't stop.
未来へと 飛ばせ叫べ コンコン
Fly toward the future, shout it out! Kon kon.
一秒も 無駄にはできないよ
We can't waste even a single second.
もっとさらけ出せ
Show more of yourself.
It's a party ハイテンションで
It's a party! With high tension!
帆を上げろ お宝出航
Raise the sails! Setting sail for treasure.
後悔したくないその思いが 追い風になる
That feeling of not wanting to regret will become a tailwind.
困ったら 思い出して
If you're in trouble, remember.
私たちがいるから 最高にハッピーな運命を yay!
Because we are here. A most happy destiny! Yay!
目と目でエンジョイタイム
Eye to eye, it's enjoy time.
気分も高まる It's all right
Your mood will rise too. It's all right.
バイブスは 最高潮 せーのでみんなで Oh yay!
The vibes are at their peak. Ready, everyone? Oh yay!
両手を挙げましょう 万々歳
Let's raise our hands. Hurrah!
まだまだこれでは物足りない
This is still not enough.
内気なそこの君 こっちおいで
You there, the shy one, come over here.
古今東西の老若男女
Men and women of all ages from all times and places.
楽しいことが 一番でしょ
Fun things are the best, right?
少しタガを 外してみましょう
Let's try cutting loose a little.
ようこそワンダーランド
Welcome to wonderland.
今日から一歩一歩踏み出せばきっと
If you start taking steps from today, surely,
人生の経験値 ゲット
you'll get life experience points.
ふとした何気ないことだって
Even the most casual things,
多分数年 笑えるさ
you'll probably be able to laugh at in a few years.
イマダ イマダ ゲッタチャンスだ 夢を掴もう
Now's the time! Now's the time! Get a chance and grab your dream.
明日から 紙吹雪フィーバー
Starting tomorrow, it's confetti fever.
想像したことない出来事が...
Events you've never imagined...
いつだって　きっと
Always, surely
回ってるさ
It's spinning around
シンガソングで心躍らせ
With a sing-a-song to make your heart dance
ポジティブにさあ面舵いっぱい
Stay positive, now hard-a-starboard
気持ち晴れ渡るその瞬間
The moment your feelings clear up
全速前進だ
Full speed ahead
いつだってひとりじゃない
You're never alone
私たちと一緒にさ
Together with us
ここでハッピーな人生を　イェーイ！
Live a happy life here, yay!
みんなでハッピーな人生を
Let's all have a happy life
イェーイ！
Yay!
あれれ　おかしな鼓動ドキドキは
Wait, what's this strange heartbeat?
君の腕の中で溢れだす
It overflows within your arms
ポロリ　こぼれた涙さくらんぼ
A cherry tear falls
もっとギュッと抱きしめてて
Hold me tighter and tighter
好き好き好き　好き好き好き
I love you, love you, love you...
好き好き好き　好き好き好き　ハイハイ！
I love you, love you, love you... High, high!
好き好き好き　好き好き好き
I love you, love you, love you...
好き好き好き　好き好き好き　ギュギュッ
I love you, love you, love you... Gyu gyu!
まだまだかな　君のハート
Is it not time yet? Your heart...
ちょっとすっぱい　本当？
Is a bit sour. Really?
おやおやおや　待ちきれない
Oh my, oh my, oh my, I can't wait
このままじゃ　ええ　もっと
At this rate... Eh? More?
すました顔で　決めて　決めて
With a serious face, decide, decide
とまどう振りは　やだよ
Don't pretend to be confused
なにげなく　ふわっと　ふわっと
Casually, lightly, lightly
手をまわして　そっと近づく
Put your hands around me and gently come closer
本当はね　ずっと好きだったの　内緒だね
Actually, I've always loved you. It's a secret, okay?
イェイ！
Yay!
あれれ　小さな胸が震えてる
Oh? My small heart is trembling
抱きしめてくれたら　飛んじゃうよ
If you hold me, I'll fly away
夢で見てたのより　切ないね
It's more painful than in my dreams
心もっと　そう　ギュッとしてて
Squeeze my heart more, like that
ポロリ　落ちた涙溢れちゃう
Overflowing tears fall
大人になるための　痛みかな
Is this the pain of growing up?
君に触れられた　ホッペ赤いクッキー
My cheek you touched is like a red cookie
ちょっとだけ　待ってて
Wait just a little bit
好き好き好き　好き好き好き
I love you, love you, love you...
好き好き好き　好き好き好き　ハイハイ！
I love you, love you, love you... High, high!
好き好き好き　好き好き好き
I love you, love you, love you...
好き好き好き　好き好き好き　ギュギュッ
I love you, love you, love you... Gyu gyu!
やだやだやだ　余所見はやだ
No, no, no, don't look elsewhere
夢中でいて　ブッブー！
Stay obsessed with me. Beep-beep!
ハラハラハラ　私はまだ
My heart is pounding, I'm still...
子供だもん　でも
Just a child, but...
君の余裕が　クサッと　クサッと
Your composure pierces me...
胸の奥に　刺さるよ
Pierces deep into my heart
そんな私　ズバッと　ズバッと
Make me change completely...
変身させてね　優しいキスで
With a gentle kiss
なんだかね　キュンとしちゃう　初めてだよ　イェイ！
Somehow, my heart is throbbing. It's my first time. Yay!
あれれ　唇震えている
Oh? My lips are trembling
君のまつげが　瞳に映る
Your eyelashes are reflected in my eyes
鼓動右肩上がり　急上昇
My heartbeat is soaring rapidly
だけじゃないよ　ちょっぴり幸せ
It's not just that, I'm quite happy
時が　止まる瞬間に
At the moment time stops
壊れそうな心　解かさ
The heart that's about to break melts
赤く弾けた私さくらんぼ
I popped red, a cherry
君とずっと繋がってたい
I want to be connected with you forever
神様　この唇は彼と出会うために　生まれてきたのですね　イェイ！
God, these lips were born to meet him, weren't they? Yay!
すました顔で　決めて　決めて
With a serious face, decide, decide
とまどう振りは　やだよ
Don't pretend to be confused
なにげなく　ふわっと　ふわっと
Casually, lightly, lightly
手をまわして　そっと近づく
Put your hands around me and gently come closer
だってね　こんなの初めてなの　内緒だよ　やったー！
Because, this is my first time. It's a secret. Yay!
あれれ　おかしな鼓動ドキドキは
Wait, what's this strange heartbeat?
君の腕の中で溢れだす
It overflows within your arms
ポロリ　こぼれた涙さくらんぼ
A cherry tear falls
もっとギュッと抱きしめてて
Hold me tighter and tighter
世界が　ぐるり回ってる
The world is spinning around
ふわふわ夢心地風任せ
Fluffy, dreamy feeling, leave it to the wind
ずっと待ってた恋は止まらない
The love I've been waiting for won't stop
だから　ずっと離さないで
So don't ever let me go
好き好き好き　好き好き好き
I love you, love you, love you...
好き好き好き　好き好き好き　ハイハイ！
I love you, love you, love you... High, high!
好き好き好き　好き好き好き
I love you, love you, love you...
好き好き好き　好き好き好き　ギュギュッ
I love you, love you, love you... Gyu gyu!
Sweets parade
歌：宝鐘マリン・姫森ルーナ
Vocals: Houshou Marine, Himemori Luna
あいうえおかした
A-I-U-E-O sweets were served
かきくけこんなにも
Ka-ki-ku-ke this much
さしすせソフトクリーム
Sa-shi-su-se soft-serve ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
Let's feel it in our souls
たちつて灯ろうできた
Ta-chi-tsu-te lanterns are ready
なにぬねのりしお
Na-ni-nu-ne seaweed salt
はひふへホッとバイト
Ha-hi-fu-he a warm bite
みんなでぬくぬく
Toasty warm together
ショートケーキ小分けにして
Divide up the strawberry shortcake
キャンディーペロペロ
Licking lollipops
チョコレートの川で
In a river of chocolate
綿菓子雲みた
I saw cotton candy clouds
アイスクリームと
With ice cream
プリンのお城で
In a castle of pudding
カスタードたぬき
Custard tanuki
二人のランデブー
A rendezvous for the two of us
パフェにサンデー
Parfait and sundae
あんこもハッピー
Sweet bean paste is also happy
たい焼きにクリーム
Taiyaki and cream
こまごまドロップ
Scattered drops
カップケーキから
From cupcakes
いちごあめまで
To strawberry candy
極上なスイーツ
Exquisite sweets
仲良くなれるよ
We'll become good friends
ふんわり
Softly
夢見てごらん
Take a look at your dreams
キャラメル
Caramel
みたいにくっつこう
Let's stick together like that
まみむめモンブラン
Ma-mi-mu-me Mont Blanc
やいゆえヨーグルト
Ya-i-yu-e Yogurt
らりるれロールケーキ
Ra-ri-ru-re roll cake
わたぬきとキスを
A kiss with Watanuki
あいうえおかした
A-I-U-E-O sweets were served
かきくけこんなにも
Ka-ki-ku-ke this much
さしすせソフトクリーム
Sa-shi-su-se soft-serve ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
Let's feel it in our souls
のんびり早出
Carefree early start
焼き海苔炙って
Toasting some roasted seaweed
おにぎりコロコロ
Rice balls rolling around
友達ほかほか
Warm and toasty friends
もみじまんじゅうと
With maple leaf buns
あんパンお月様
And red bean bun moon
わたぬきに始まり
Starting with Watanuki
わたぬきに終わる日々
Days ending with Watanuki
じんわり
Gradually
見つめてごらん
Try staring at it
甘くて
The sweet
苦い夕焼けは
And bitter sunset
たちつて灯ろうできた
Ta-chi-tsu-te lanterns are ready
なにぬねのりしお
Na-ni-nu-ne seaweed salt
はひふへホッとバイト
Ha-hi-fu-he a warm bite
みんなでぬくぬく
Toasty warm together
まみむめモンブラン
Ma-mi-mu-me Mont Blanc
やいゆえヨーグルト
Ya-i-yu-e Yogurt
らりるれロールケーキ
Ra-ri-ru-re roll cake
わたぬきとキスを
A kiss with Watanuki
虹色和風楼
Rainbow-colored Japanese-style tower
ボンボン ムッシュ わたぬきパイ
Bon bon, monsieur, Watanuki pie
シュークリーム バナナジェリー
Cream puffs, banana jelly
ボマロハ わたぬき
Bomaroha Watanuki
ホットケーキ バウムクーヘン
Pancakes, Baumkuchen
わたぬき わたぬき
Watanuki, Watanuki
わたわたぬきクレープ
Wata-watanuki crepe
わたぬき わたぬき
Watanuki, Watanuki
わたぬきとごはん
Watanuki and a meal
わたぬきとおやつ
Watanuki and a snack
わたぬきと肉まん
Watanuki and a meat bun
わたぬきと北京ダック
Watanuki and Peking duck
目刺しわたぬき
Dried sardine Watanuki
わたぬきシロップ
Watanuki syrup
金時わたぬき
Kintoki Watanuki
あまりわたぬき団子
Leftover Watanuki dumplings
ふんわり
Softly
思い出色
Color of memories
ハチミツ
Honey
みたいにとろける
Melting away like that
あいうえおかした
A-I-U-E-O sweets were served
かきくけこんなにも
Ka-ki-ku-ke this much
さしすせソフトクリーム
Sa-shi-su-se soft-serve ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
Let's feel it in our souls
たちつて灯ろうできた
Ta-chi-tsu-te lanterns are ready
なにぬねのりしお
Na-ni-nu-ne seaweed salt
はひふへホッとバイト
Ha-hi-fu-he a warm bite
二人でぬくぬく
Toasty warm together
まみむめモンブラン
Ma-mi-mu-me Mont Blanc
やいゆえヨーグルト
Ya-i-yu-e Yogurt
らりるれロールケーキ
Ra-ri-ru-re roll cake
わたぬきとキスを
A kiss with Watanuki
わたぬきの甘味と
With Watanuki's sweetness
わたぬきの苦味
And Watanuki's bitterness
わたぬきの酸味で
And Watanuki's acidity
好き好きラブコンボ
I love it, love combo
サウスポー
歌：宝鐘マリン・戌神ころね
Southpaw
Vocals: Houshou Marine, Inugami Korone
背番号1のすごいやつが相手
The opponent is that amazing guy with number 1
フラミンゴみたい ひょいと一本足で
Like a flamingo, standing on one leg
スーパースターのお出ましに
The superstar makes his appearance
ベンチのサインは敬遠
The sign from the bench is "intentional walk"
なんだけど 逃げちゃ嫌だわ
But... I don't want you to run away.
男ならここで 逃げの一手だけど
If it were a man, he'd make a run for it now.
女にはそんな ことはできはしない
But a woman could never do such a thing.
弱気なサインに首を振り
Shaking my head at a sign of weakness,
得意の魔球を投げ込むだけよ
I'll just throw my best magic ball.
さわやか 勝負よ
A clean, fair fight!
しんと静まった
Falling into a hush...
スタジアム
The stadium.
静寂の一瞬よ
A moment of total silence.
熱い勝負は
This heated match...
恋の火ぶたよ
Is the spark of love!
胸の鼓動がドキドキ 目先はクラクラ 負けそう 負けそう
My heart is pounding, my head is spinning, I'm gonna lose, I'm gonna lose!
私ピンクのサウスポー
I'm the pink southpaw!
きりきり舞いよ きりきり舞いよ
Spinning 'round and 'round, 'round and 'round!
魔球は 魔球は
The magic ball, the magic ball...
ハリケーン
Is a hurricane!
背番号1の すごいやつが笑う
That amazing guy with number 1 on his back smiles.
おちょこちょい投げて みろとやつが笑う
He smiles and tells me to throw a clumsy pitch.
しばらくお色気さよなら
Farewell to charm for a while,
でっかい相手をしとめるまでは
Until I take down this big opponent!
ちょっとおあずけ
It's on hold for a bit!
さあ駆け抜ける
Now, running through...
サスペンス
The suspense.
スリルの瞬間よ
It's a moment of pure thrill.
熱い視線が
These burning gazes...
絡みあったら
Once they've intertwined!
白い火花がパチパチ 心はメラメラ 燃えそう 燃えそう
White sparks are popping, my heart is blazing, I'm gonna burn, I'm gonna burn!
私ピンクのサウスポー
I'm the pink southpaw!
きりきり舞いよ きりきり舞いよ
Spinning 'round and 'round, 'round and 'round!
魔球は 魔球は
The magic ball, the magic ball...
ハリケーン
Is a hurricane!
ロキ
Houshou Marine Birthday 3D Live
Loki
宝鐘マリン × AZKi
Houshou Marine × AZKi
さあ、眠眠打破
Now, drink a Min Min Daha.
昼夜逆転
Day and night reversed.
VOX AC30w
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンドの仲間にハロー
Subculture boy with a Telecaster says hello to his bandmates.
アルバイトはネクラモード
At his part-time job, he's in gloomy mode.
対バンには下心
Hidden motives for the rival band.
人見知り宣言で逃げる気かボーイ
Planning to run away with a 'shyness declaration,' boy?
ゆとりお坊ちゃん お嬢ちゃん お金も才能も なまじあるだけ厄介でやんす
Spoiled boys and girls, having money and talent is just a hassle.
Boys be ambitious
はいはい
Yeah, yeah.
ライクアローリングストーン
Like a rolling stone.
長い前髪 君誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者
Follower.
勘違いすんな 教祖はおまえだ
Don't get it wrong, the leader is you.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
Roki-Roki's rock 'n' rock 'n' roll, that electric guitar you're strumming... Don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ君のすべてを さらけ出してみせろよ
Come on, show me everything you've got!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-Roki's rock 'n' rock 'n' roll.
さあ、日進月歩
Now, making steady progress.
いい曲書いてる？
Writing good songs?
動員増えてる？
Are the crowds growing?
知名度あるけど人気はそんなにないから色々大変ですね
You're known, but not that popular, so it must be tough.
はっきり言えば匿名アイコン
Frankly speaking, an anonymous icon.
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
A real-life photo you won't clearly show.
愛おしいほど自意識過剰ボーイ
So endearingly self-conscious, boy.
ぶっちゃけどれだけ賢くあざとくやったって 10年後にはメイクは落ちてんだよ
Honestly, no matter how smart or cunning you are, in ten years, the makeup will be gone.
Boys be ambitious
はいはい
Yeah, yeah.
ライクアゾンビメン
Like a zombie man.
逝けぬくたばらぬ 君の手をセルフィー
Can't go, won't die, a selfie of your hand.
セルフィー
Selfie.
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにな
Don't you go dying now, either of us.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Loki loki no rock'n'rock'n'roll
掻き鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
The electric guitar strumming along
Don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ目の前のあの子を
Now, that girl right in front of you
撃ち抜いて見せろよ
Go ahead and shoot her through
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Loki loki no rock'n'rock'n'roll
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
I can't be satisfied with just small talk
スタジオに運ばれた面良男（つらおとこ）とは
With the handsome guy carried into the studio
足指（あしゆび）踏みしめプレッシャーでいっぱい
Feet planted firm, full of pressure
節操は昨日から飾られた最期まで用心
Watch your principles from yesterday until the end
は？
Huh?
寝ると言えば Baby Baby Baby Baby
When I say sleep Baby Baby Baby Baby
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにナ
Don't you go dying now, for both of us
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Loki loki no rock'n'rock'n'roll
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
The electric guitar strumming along
Don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ君のすべてを曝け出してみせろよ
Now, show me everything you've got
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Loki loki no rock'n'rock'n'roll
ロキロキの...
Loki loki no...
ロックンロックンロール
Rock'n'rock'n'roll
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you go dying
死にたかねえのはお互い様！
Neither of us wants to die!
Smile!
Sweet!
Sister!
Sadistic!
Surprise!
Service!
We are スティーレ！！
We are Stile!!
さあ 扉を開けて 未知なるパラダイス
Now, open the door to an unknown paradise
体験しよう おいで おいでよ
Come and experience it, come on over
君を待つのは 不思議なオアシス
What awaits you is a mysterious oasis
びっくり自由に ちょっぴりスパイス
Full of surprise and freedom, and a little spice
くるん くるん かき混ぜちゃうんだ
Round and round, I'll mix it all up
ぷるん ぷるん とっておきのフレーバー
Jiggly jiggly, my very best flavor
サービス サービス ほほおみたいな
Service, service, like a little surprise
おもてなし 心こめて
Hospitality from the bottom of my heart
Welcome to 私たちと一緒に
Welcome to! Together with us
めくるめく ワンダーデイリー
A dazzling wonder daily
愛情ましもし 万能なでなで
Extra affection, all-purpose head-pats
誠心誠意 努めます！
We will serve you with all our heart!
Yes! 君の元気チャージに一役買えるかな
Yes! I hope I can help recharge your energy
ひと役買えるから
I can play a part
恋した感じも 会いた感じも
The feeling of love, the feeling of meeting
意外と悪くないでしょ
It's not so bad, right?
ボーノ ボーノ ブレンドしたい
Buono buono, I want to blend
君にキュンキュンキュン
Going kyun-kyun-kyun for you
ハートにパンチパンチパンチ
A punch-punch-punch to your heart
ボーノ ボーノ ブレンドしたい
Buono buono, I want to blend
お口に合いますか
Is it to your liking?
お口に合いますか…い！
Is it to your liking...!
ボナペティ
Bon appétit
千客万来！
Business is booming!
ちょっと長めの褒めいながらも
While giving a bit of a long compliment
いつだって需要は斜め上
The demand is always off the charts
そんじゃ行か法 ホントの私は
Well then, the real me is
シークレットモードで営業中
Currently operating in secret mode
くるん くるん かき混ぜて もっと
Round and round, mix it more
くるん くるん 君仕様のフレーバー
Round and round, a flavor just for you
サービス サービス 極上タイム
Service, service, premium time
淑女はかくあるべき
A lady should be like this
Welcome to 私たちの店に
Welcome to our shop
本日も ようこそ
Welcome again today
お帰り待ってた リピート嬉しいね
I was waiting for your return, happy to see you again
全店 歓迎！
Welcome to the whole shop!
君のお疲れ様に
For all your hard work
ぴったりのレシピで
With the perfect recipe
こういうのどうかな ああいうのありかな
How about this? Or maybe that?
喜んでもらえるかな
I hope you'll like it
Smile!
Sweet!
Sister!
Sadistic!
Small!
Strange!
Serious!
Selfish!
Secret!
Super girl!
We are スティーレ！！
We are Stile!!
さあ 扉を開けて
Now, open the door
異界のパラダイス
A paradise from another world
怖がらずにおいで おいで
Don't be afraid, come on in, come in
さあ いつもどおりの毎日に
Now, to your usual daily life,
彩りと遊び心を
add color and a playful spirit
召し上がれ ブレンドを
Please enjoy this blend
ウェルカム トゥ マイ 私たちと一緒に
Welcome to my... along with us,
めくるめくワンダーランド
to a dazzling wonderland
あまい あまい マシュマロ マシュマロ
Sweet, sweet marshmallows, marshmallows
鼻は なでなで 精一杯 努めます
Pats on the nose, I'll do my absolute best
イエス 君の元気チャージに
Yes, to charge up your energy,
いざ役を返るから
I'll take on the role now
恋した感じも 会いた感じも
The feeling of love, the feeling of wanting to meet,
意外と悪くないでしょ
it's not so bad, is it?
バーボン ブレンド したい君に
For you who wants a Bourbon Blend
きゅんきゅんきゅん ハートに パンパンパンチ
Heart-throbbing, a bang-bang-punch to the heart
バーボン ブレンド スタイル
Bourbon Blend style
お口に合いますか？
Is it to your liking?
あま利き風 責めてね
At least, let the sweet tasting wind...
お口に アンサーを
An answer to your mouth
白い雪のプリンセスは
The Snow White Princess is
宝鐘マリン・雪花ラミィ
Houshou Marine, Yukihana Lamy
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall,
世界で一番可愛くなるのはやめてよ
don't become the most beautiful in the world.
棘のような視線で射る
Shoot me with a gaze like thorns.
優しいふりした彼女が
She, who pretended to be kind,
素敵な晩餐もてなした
offered a wonderful dinner.
そっと口に含むと 笑み
With a soft bite, a smile.
薄れゆく 意識の中で
Within my fading consciousness,
夢を見てる いつかのおとぎ話
I'm dreaming of a fairy tale from long ago.
時が止まる
Time stops.
お願いキスで目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss,
白い棺から連れ出すように
as if to lead me out of the white coffin.
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマチックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance.
祈っても君はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, you still haven't come.
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall,
ネクタイ任せて頬に挨拶するから
I'll leave the tie to you and greet your cheek,
妬みを買われてしまった
for I have incurred envy.
七つの小人はいるけど
The seven dwarves are here, but
助ける素振りしらんぷり
they feign ignorance of any attempt to help.
そっと首を掴まれ 笑み
With my neck softly grabbed, a smile.
一粒の 涙さえも
Even a single teardrop,
拭えなくて 呼吸もままならない
I cannot wipe away, and I can hardly breathe.
視界失せた
My vision is lost.
消えそうだから早く駆けてほしいの
I'm about to disappear, so I want you to run to me quickly.
訳は聞かないで 答えられない
Don't ask why; I cannot answer.
望まない憎まれは深い愛の事情
The unwanted spite is a deep love's circumstance.
もうすぐでいなくなるのかな
I wonder if I'll be gone soon.
途切れていく 命の音
The sound of life is fading out.
毒りんごを 食した少女のように
Like the girl who ate the poisoned apple,
眠りにつく
I fall into a slumber.
お願いキスで目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss.
胸の中の声 届きますか
Will the voice in my heart reach you?
階段を登ったらドアを開けるだけで
Just climbing the stairs and opening the door,
見つかるよ ああ
you'll find it, ah.
お願いキスで目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss,
白い棺から連れ出すように
as if to lead me out of the white coffin.
突き刺さる...
The piercing...
…君のドルチェ＆ガッバーナの
...it's because of your Dolce & Gabbana
その香水のせいだよ
perfume.
別に君を求めてないけど
I'm not looking for you or anything,
横にいられると思い出す
but when you're by my side, I remember.
君のドルチェ＆ガッバーナのその香水のせいだよ
It's because of your Dolce & Gabbana perfume.
じょーじょーゆーじょー
Amazing friendship!
ばじまじかいちょー
Totally in high spirits!
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ
Na na na na na na na na na na na na na na na
ヒャダインのじょーじょーゆーじょー
Hyadain's Amazing Friendship
はい！いっちゃいましょう！
Alright! Let's go!
君はベストフレンド！
You're my best friend!
ちょっとふざけてみたら
When I mess around a little,
もっとふざけ返してくる
you mess around even more back at me.
ランララ　居心地いいったらない
Lan lala, it couldn't be more comfortable.
嫌なことあったって
Even when something bad happens,
そこは忘れちゃうんだ
I end up forgetting about it there.
ランララ　いっせーのーでジャンジャンやりましょう
Lan lala, one, two, let's keep it going!
24時間一緒でも問題ない
It's no problem even if we're together for 24 hours.
まるで双子か親子かクローン細胞
Just like twins, parent and child, or cloned cells.
これじゃあ熱中する必要とかなくなくない？
Doesn't this mean there's no need to be so obsessed?
それとこれとは全く全く別問題！
That and this are completely, completely different issues!
喧嘩しちゃった時も
Even when we've had a fight,
かなり凹んだ時も
or when I'm feeling really down,
一人でいたいような時も
or even when I feel like being alone,
ふと気づけば近くにいるしなまもろとも
before I know it, you're near, and we're in this together.
なんでだろ　側にいたいんだ
I wonder why I want to be by your side.
君と一緒なら
If I'm with you,
時給100倍さ
the value of my time increases a hundredfold!
楽しいな　楽しすぎるんだ
It's fun, it's just too much fun.
さすが最強フレンド　Hey!
As expected of the strongest friend! Hey!
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ　ヤバいシンクロ率
Na na na na na na na na, crazy synchronization rate!
いつも大騒ぎ　かなりご近所迷惑
Always making a fuss, quite a nuisance to the neighbors.
今何時？　一に二に三！
What time is it? One, two, three!
わけわかんないない　ソレドシラソ
I don't understand it at all! So-Re-Do-Si-La-So!
想像以上なんて愉快最高
More than I imagined, it's the best fun ever!
あだこだ言ってても友達　ワッショイ！
Even if we bicker about this and that, we're friends! Wasshoi!
じょーじょーゆーじょー　ばじまじかいちょー
Amazing friendship! Totally in high spirits!
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ
Na na na na na na na na na na na na na na na
マリフレのじょーじょーゆーじょー、2番もお聞きください！
Please listen to the second verse of Mari-Flare's "Joujou Yuujou"!
同じテレビ見てて　メールで実況中継
Watching the same TV show, doing a live commentary via text.
ランララ　CM入れば電話タイム
Lan lala, once the commercials start, it's phone time.
遠くにいる時でも　近くに感じてるんだ
Even when we're far apart, I feel you close by.
ランララ　ヨロシクガンガン行きましょう
Lan lala, let's keep going strong!
ヤバい弁当忘れたカンパして
Oh no, I forgot my lunch! Give me some money.
やだよ命の源焼きそばパン
No way! This yakisoba bread is my life force.
ちょいと友達なんでしょごもっともな
Hey, aren't we friends? You're quite right.
それとこれとは全く全く別問題！
That and this are completely, completely different issues!
変な気は使わない　好色なんか知らない
We don't worry about being weird, and we don't care about looks.
でも傷つけたりはしない
But we would never hurt each other.
神様マジありがとうゲットできたマブダチ
God, thank you so much! I've found a true friend.
やったあ　おっしゃー　マイフレンド
Yay! Alright! My friend!
最高潮！　不謹慎崩壊
At our peak! Breaking the rules!
涙が出るくらい　笑い疲れちゃうんだ
I'm getting tired from laughing so much I'm in tears.
何しよう？　何をしましょうか？
What should we do? What shall we do?
しりとりレッツゴー！　わー！
Shiritori, let's go! Whoo!
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ　南海ライナー
Na na na na na na na na, Nankai Liner!
ラブラブゴリラ
Lovey-dovey Gorilla!
なんだその生き物
What kind of creature is that?
もう飽きた　マジかよヨロレヒ
I'm bored already. Seriously? Yodel-ay-hee!
意味もないない　ソレドシラソ
It makes no sense at all! So-Re-Do-Si-La-So!
友達数と暑苦しく思ってた
I used to think having friends was just annoying...
でもでも　やっぱ言えないや　Because
But, but... I still can't say it, because...
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ
Na na na na na na na na na na na na na na na
はい！いっちゃいましょう！
Alright! Let's go!
君はベストフレンド！
You're my best friend!
なんでだろ　側にいたいんだ
I wonder why I want to be by your side.
君と一緒なら
If I'm with you,
時給100倍さ
the value of my time increases a hundredfold!
楽しいな　楽しすぎるんだ
It's fun, it's just too much fun.
さすが最強フレンド　Hey!
As expected of the strongest friend! Hey!
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ　ヤバいシンクロ率
Na na na na na na na na, crazy synchronization rate!
いつも大騒ぎ　かなりご近所迷惑
Always making a fuss, quite a nuisance to the neighbors.
今何時？　一に二に三！
What time is it? One, two, three!
わけわかんないない　ソレドシラソ
I don't understand it at all! So-Re-Do-Si-La-So!
想像以上なんて愉快最高
More than I imagined, it's the best fun ever!
あだこだ言ってても友達　ワッショイ！
Even if we bicker about this and that, we're friends! Wasshoi!
じょーじょーゆーじょー　ばじまじかいちょー
Amazing friendship! Totally in high spirits!
ジャジャジャジャジャン！
Ja ja ja ja jan!
ハロニホン　こんにちは　ボンジュール　グーテンターク　アロハ！
Halo-nihon, hello, bonjour, guten tag, aloha!
小さな頃に憧れた　僕を導き夢見たヒロイン
The heroine I admired and dreamed of when I was little
何でもなれると信じてた　神様も見えてた不思議
I believed I could become anything, a miracle where I could even see God
今　その中で流れていく　時の速さの低位で
Now, flowing within it, at the low speed of time
忘れかけた奇跡を　もう一度信じられたら
If I could believe in the forgotten miracle once again...
響け　波のメロディ
Resonate, melody of the waves
嬉しい気持ち　いつでもベイビー　優しく包むこの街
A happy feeling, always baby, this town that gently embraces us
最後は魔法を解かさない　明日の光射すディープ・ブルー
Don't let the magic break at the end, the light of tomorrow shines, Deep Blue
ハロニホン　こんにちは　ボンジュール　グーテンターク　アロハ！
Halo-nihon, hello, bonjour, guten tag, aloha!
幼き時と変わらない　溢れる青と海が生まれるスマイル
Unchanged since childhood, a smile born from the overflowing blue and the sea
昨日喧嘩した友達も　明日には笑うよ　アハハハ
Friends I fought with yesterday will laugh tomorrow, ahahaha
海の呼吸に身を寄せて　目を閉じて感じようよ
Let's lean into the ocean's breath, close our eyes and feel it
暗闇に響く歌　優しく感じられたら
If I could feel the song echoing in the darkness gently...
深く　夢にダイブ
Dive deep into the dream
激しい愛し　心のままに　笑顔で溢れてる街
Intense love, as your heart desires, a town overflowing with smiles
海いっぱいの愛も届けたい　伝わっていくよディープ・ブルー
I want to deliver sea-full of love, it's being conveyed, Deep Blue
ハイ！
Hi!
ハイハイ！
Hi hi!
ハイハイハイ！
Hi hi hi!
もっと！
More!
まだまだ！
More and more!
うーん、ラッキー！
Ooh, lucky!
海の心を心から　繋がる所を愛に
From the heart of the sea, making the connection place into love
忘れないで奇跡を　君の側で感じるさ
Don't forget the miracle, I'll feel it by your side
届けて　水のリズム
Deliver it, the rhythm of water
響け　波のメロディ
Resonate, melody of the waves
踊れ　歌え　舞い上がるまで　海より深い愛の街
Dance, sing until you soar, a town of love deeper than the sea
揺れる　触れる　その柔らかさ　ありがとうを伝えたい
Swaying, touching, that softness, I want to say thank you
嬉しい気持ち　いつでもベイビー　優しく包むこの街
A happy feeling, always baby, this town that gently embraces us
最後は魔法を解かさない　明日の光射すディープ・ブルー
Don't let the magic break at the end, the light of tomorrow shines, Deep Blue
ハロニホン　こんにちは　ボンジュール　グーテンターク　アロハ！
Halo-nihon, hello, bonjour, guten tag, aloha!
女々しくて　女々しくて　女々しくて
Girlish, girlish, girlish
つらいよォォォォォ！
It's so painful!
僕のことをからかったの？　あんなに好きと言ったのに
Were you making fun of me? Even though you said you liked me so much
奴のどこを気に入ったの？　僕はもういらないの？
What part of him did you like? Am I not needed anymore?
君と手を繋ぎ踊りたい　たくさんの人混みの中で
I want to hold your hand and dance amidst a large crowd
君の笑顔だけが　輝いて
Only your smile shines bright
愛されたいねきっと見過ごした　君のシグナルもう一度
I want to be loved, I probably missed it, your signal once more
気まぐれからでも構わない　君といたいから
I don't care if it's just a whim, because I want to be with you
女々しくて　女々しくて　光を浴びて
Girlish, girlish, bathing in the light
女々しくて　女々しくて　恋の歌歌って
Girlish, girlish, singing a love song
女々しくて　女々しくて　辿り着いたこの世界はもう
Girlish, girlish, this world I've reached is already...
女々しくて　女々しくて　女々しくて　つらいよ
Girlish, girlish, girlish, it's so painful
今日の驚きを忘れよう
Let's forget today's surprises
昨日の震えない闇など
Like the darkness of yesterday that didn't tremble
君は誰を継ぎ　誰と心を汲み交わす
Who will you succeed, and with whom will you exchange your heart?
本当は抱き合って眠りたい
Actually, I want to fall asleep in your arms
カラカラに乾いた心を
This bone-dry heart...
君の美しさで潤わして
...moisten it with your beauty
恋に焦がれ　いつもミスをした
Longing for love, I always made mistakes
女の子心　雲のよう
A girl's heart is like a cloud
惚れた腫れた　狭い心が　また乱れている
In love and infatuated, my narrow heart is in disarray again
女（めめしく）
Jealousy...
女々しくて　女々しくて　誰を見つめ
Effeminate, effeminate, who are you looking at?
女々しくて　女々しくて　君が笑顔で
Effeminate, effeminate, with your smile...
女々しくて　女々しくて　不条理なリフレインに
Effeminate, effeminate, in this absurd refrain...
胸はもう
...my heart is already...
女々しくて　女々しくて　辛いよ
Effeminate, effeminate, it's painful
俺という星に落としてやるさ
I'll drop you onto the star that is me.
美しい花には棘があるんだよ
Beautiful flowers have thorns.
おはよう　かわいいね　〇しちゃうよ
Good morning. You're cute. I'll ○ you.
全然言葉が思いつかない
I can't think of any words at all.
お仕置きが足りなかったかな
Was the punishment not enough?
そんなに潤んだ瞳で見ても　認知してあげない
Even if you look at me with such teary eyes, I won't recognize you.
愛情という名の罠で君が欲しい
I want you in a trap called love
僕の心　射抜くのよ
Pierce through my heart
騙されたって　どうぞ構わない
Even if I'm deceived, I don't mind
君といれるなら
If I can be with you
愛されたいね　きっと見過ごした
I want to be loved, I surely overlooked...
君のシグナル　もう一度
...your signal, once more
気まぐれかな　でも構わない
Is it a whim? But I don't mind
君といたいから
Because I want to be with you
女々しくて　女々しくて　光を浴びて
Effeminate, effeminate, bathed in light
女々しくて　女々しくて　恋の歌歌って
Effeminate, effeminate, singing a love song
女々しくて　女々しくて　いざ辿り着いたこの世界はもう
Effeminate, effeminate, this world I've finally reached is already...
女々しくて　女々しくて　辛いよ
Effeminate, effeminate, it's painful
海賊なら　Yo-Ho! 踊れ　叫べ　Yo-Ho!
If you're a pirate, Yo-Ho! Dance, scream, Yo-Ho!
さあ　今　旗のもとへ
Now, come under the flag
宝鐘海賊団
The Houshou Pirates
出航！ (Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!)
Set sail! (Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!)
踊るアホイに見るアホイ　全速前進だ！
Dancing ahoy, watching ahoy, full speed ahead!
進め！太陽燦々　大航海日和だ
Advance! The sun is shining, it's a great day for a voyage
歌え！最高のテンション　波の音に乗せ　ドンブラコ
Sing! Highest tension, riding the sound of the waves, donburako
海でガールズパーティー　お陰様でハッピー
Girls' party at sea, thanks to you, I'm happy
お空は毒々　キラキラ
The sky is poisonous and sparkling
山奥ボロボロマイハウスで　夢を見て
Dreaming in my worn-out house deep in the mountains
あ、神様！　いつかこのマリンを　本物の海賊にしてください！
Oh, God! Please make this Marine a real pirate someday!
声を上げて　さあ出航だ　我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voice, now let's set sail, we are the Houshou Pirates
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ　この海をジャックしちゃおう
With a compass in one hand and raising the flag, let's jack this sea
ヨソロついておいで　共にYo-Ho Yo-Ho叫ぼう
Follow along, steady as she goes, let's scream Yo-Ho Yo-Ho together
ああ　最高の日々
Ah, the best days
ようこそ我が船へ
Welcome to my ship
(Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!) 踊るアホイに見るアホイ
(Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!) Dancing ahoy, watching ahoy
1, 2, サンバ！サンバ！
1, 2, Samba! Samba!
熱く語ろうパッション　思いを解き放て
Let's talk passionately, release your thoughts
赤くひらめくファッション　形から入るタイプです
Crimson flickering fashion, I'm the type who starts with appearance
発射10秒前　走れ！ガチ恋列車
10 seconds before launch, run! Serious-love train
夕焼けも照れるわ　ギラギラ
Even the sunset is shy, dazzling
じんわり汗も滴るいい女…　だけど！
A fine woman dripping with sweat... but!
あ、神様！　船長はセンシティブだと　BANされちゃうのですね！？　はにゃー！
Oh, God! If the Captain is sensitive, she'll get banned, right!? Hanyaa!
奪われたら　取り戻せ
If it's stolen, take it back
それが宝鐘海賊団
That's the Houshou Pirate Crew
君たちとならたどり着ける
With you all, we can reach it
伝説のエルドラド
The legendary El Dorado
夜空　楽しけりゃ
If the night sky is fun
歌いヨーホーヨーホー　パーリナイ
Singing Yo-ho Yo-ho, party night
ああ　この景色
Ah, this scenery
大切な仲間よ
My precious companions
宴だ宴！　騒げや騒げ！
A feast, a feast! Make some noise!
踊る阿呆に見る阿呆！
The dancing fools and the watching fools!
同じ阿呆なら飲まなきゃ損損！
If we're both fools, we'd lose if we didn't drink!
酒樽片手に行きますよ！
With a sake barrel in hand, here we go!
それ　アホイ！　アホイ！
So, Ahoy! Ahoy!
宝鐘マリン！
Houshou Marine!
世界で一番？
Number one in the world?
メスガキ！メスガキ！
Mesugaki! Mesugaki!
エロガキ！エロガキ！
Erogaki! Erogaki!
バキュバコーン！
Bakyubakoon!
お嬢ちゃん、パンツ何色？
Little miss, what color are your panties?
お宝お宝！
Treasure, treasure!
まずい！まずい！
Oh no! Oh no!
撫でますわ〜！
I'll pet you~!
船長のちょっといいとこ見てみたい！
I want to see the Captain's good side!
あははは！　うふふふ！
Ahahaha! Uhuhuhu!
セクシービーム！
Sexy Beam!
いや〜んまいっちんぐ！
Oh~ Maichingu!
だっちゅーの！
Datchu-no!
サビサビシー！
Sabi-sabishi!
萌え萌えキュン！
Moe moe kyun!
出会って５秒で...
5 seconds after meeting...
もう！船長は君たちをそんな子に育てた覚えはありません！
Geez! I don't remember raising you guys to be like that!
本当にね！
Seriously!
立てば自習、座れば昭和、歩く姿はセンシティブ
Standing is self-study, sitting is Showa era, walking is sensitive
夢を見ようよ　この船で　後悔なんてさせない
Let's dream on this ship, I won't let you regret it
君たちのおかげで私は　船長になれるから
Because of you all, I can be the Captain
見せてあげるよ船長キャノン！　行っけーーー！
I'll show you, Captain Cannon! Goooo!
声を上げて　さあ出航だ　我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voice, let's set sail, we are the Houshou Pirate Crew
コンパス片手に旗を揚げ　この海をジャックしちゃお
With compass in hand, raise the flag, let's hijack this sea!
夜空ついておいで　共にヨーホーヨーホー叫ぼう
Follow the night sky, let's shout Yo-ho Yo-ho together
ああ　最高の日々
Ah, the greatest days
ようこそ我が船へ
Welcome to my ship
宝鐘の海賊団
The Houshou Pirate Crew
それではいきますよ！
Alright, here we go!
出航ーーー！
Set saaaail!
はい！まだ帰らないでくださいよ！
Wait! Please don't leave yet!
ここからは告知とグッズのお知らせです。
From here, it's news and goods announcements.
ちゃんと最後まで見ないとにわか一味になってしまうので、しっかり見ること！
If you don't watch until the end, you'll become a fake crew member, so watch carefully!
まずはお誕生日記念グッズです。
First is the birthday commemorative goods.
初めに紹介するのはこちら！　ジャジャン！
The first thing to introduce is this! Ta-da!
船長とおそろいパーカーです！
It's a matching hoodie with the Captain!
先日お披露目した船長の新衣装とおそろいのデザインになっていますよ。
The design matches the Captain's new outfit revealed the other day.
内側の柄は、船長はチェックなんですけど、まあ君たちにチェックを着こなすのは難しいでしょう。
The inside pattern is plaid for the Captain, but well, it would be hard for you all to pull off plaid.
手加減して普通の赤にしておきました。おしゃれでしょう？
So I went easy and made it a regular red. Stylish, isn't it?
部屋着もよし、部屋に配置してマリンが脱ぎ散らかしたと妄想するもよし！
Great as loungewear, or place it in your room and imagine Marine took it off and left it there!
続いてこちら！船長とおそろいキャップです！
Next is this! The matching cap with the Captain!
こちらも船長の新衣装とおそろいになっていて、おしゃれな帽子でしょう？
This also matches the Captain's new outfit, a stylish hat, right?
トワ様のママのるるどさんも買うって言っていたので、実質るるどさんとおそろいまである。
Towa-sama's mama, Rurudo-san, said she'd buy one too, so you basically match with Rurudo-san.
さらにこちら！船長とおそろい缶バッジセット！
And here! Matching button badge set with the Captain!
船長の新衣装についている缶バッジです。
These are the button badges on the Captain's new outfit.
パーカーにつけてもよし、カバンにつけてもよし、好きなところに刺し散らかしてください！
Put them on your hoodie, or your bag, pin them wherever you like!
そしてこちら！B2お風呂ポスターです！
And this! B2 bath poster!
これはお風呂に貼れる撥水ポスターなんですよ。
This is a water-repellent poster you can stick in the bath.
お風呂でマリンに水をぶっかけ放題！こんなことが許されていいのか？
You can splash water on Marine as much as you want in the bath! Is this even allowed?
君たちとお風呂、楽しいですよ。うふ！
Taking a bath with you all is fun. Uh-huh!
さあ、内容が重いので全部セットも重い！
Well, the content is heavy, so the full set is also heavy!
でもこの重い全部セットを購入してくれた君には感謝を込めて、
But for those of you who buy this heavy full set, as a token of my gratitude,
ポストカードに直筆一言メッセージを書かせていただきます！
I'll write a handwritten short message on the postcard!
こちらは数量限定なので、なくなっちゃったら勘弁してください！
This is limited in quantity, so please forgive me if it sells out!
なくなっても一応、直筆複製メッセージ入りポストカードも手に入りますよ。
Even if it runs out, you can still get a postcard with a printed version of the handwritten message.
本当はね、ボイスをつけたかったんですけど、納期のタイミングで声が枯れ散らかしていて撮れませんでした。
Actually, I wanted to include voice lines, but my voice was completely shot by the deadline, so I couldn't record them.
でも豪華な内容なので喜んでね君たち！
But it's a gorgeous lineup, so be happy, everyone!
えー、こちら 22 時から概要欄にも記載されている BOOTH で販売開始です！要チェックですよ！
Er, sales start at 22:00 on the BOOTH linked in the description! Check it out!
続いてのお知らせはこちら！
Next announcement is this!
宝鐘マリンねんどろいどご予約受付中！
Houshou Marine Nendoroid, pre-orders now open!
海賊コートなどいろんなオプションパーツが付属されています。
It comes with various optional parts like a pirate coat.
顔やパーツを付け替えることでさまざまなシチュエーションを楽しめますよ。
You can enjoy various situations by swapping faces and parts.
ねんどろいど 宝鐘マリン ご予約受付中！
Nendoroid Houshou Marine: Pre-orders Now Open!
ポケットに忍ばせて、
Keep it in your pocket,
「ちょ、マリン、ついてきちゃダメって言っただろ！」
"Hey, Marine, I told you not to follow me!"
みたいにやり取りをすることもできます。
You can even have interactions like that.
こちらは予約期間中に生産上限数に達した場合、予約受付終了となってしまいます。
If the production limit is reached during the pre-order period, pre-orders will close.
こうなってしまったら手に入らない可能性がかなり高いので、絶対ゲットしないと損、損ですよ！
If that happens, there's a high chance you won't be able to get it, so you'll definitely be missing out if you don't get one!
本日12時から予約受付開始しておりますので、
Pre-orders started today at 12:00 PM,
グッドスマイルカンパニー公式サイトをご確認ください！
so please check the Good Smile Company official website!
最後のお知らせはこちらです！
The last announcement is this!
宝鐘マリンPC 発売決定！
Houshou Marine PC Release Decided!
宝鐘マリンPC発売決定！
Houshou Marine PC release decided!
ツクモ様から宝鐘マリン仕様のコラボPCが発売されます！
A collaboration PC with Houshou Marine specs will be released by Tsukumo!
イラスト・PCケースデザイン監修は船長のお母さん、あかさあい先生、メインデザイナーは深井涼介先生！
The illustrations and PC case design supervision are by the Captain's mother, Akasa Ai-sensei, and the main designer is Fukai Ryousuke-sensei!
お母さんと深井涼介先生は仲良しらしく、お二人のずっとも絆パワーでデザインされた愛のPCです。
Apparently, Mother and Fukai Ryousuke-sensei are close, so it's a PC of love designed with their "best friends forever" bond power.
で、このパソコン、何がすごいって、
And what's so great about this PC is...
まずね、あかさあい先生描き下ろし壁紙！
First of all, a newly drawn wallpaper by Akasa Ai-sensei!
そしてね、船長の配信のオープニングとかを手掛けてくださっている天狗ノ図先生描き下ろしオリジナルマウスカーソル！
And an original mouse cursor newly drawn by Tengunozu-sensei, who created the opening for the Captain's streams!
そして船長の録り下ろしパソコン用システムボイス付きなんです！
And it comes with newly recorded PC system voices by the Captain!
パソコンスペックは松竹梅の3パターンあるようですよ。
There seem to be three patterns for the PC specs: High, Medium, and Low tiers.
営業部長も船長のマネージャーも全世界求めている一品です！
It's an item that both the sales manager and the Captain's manager, the whole world is looking for!
発売販売期間は2021年秋冬を予定しております。
The release and sales period is scheduled for Fall/Winter 2021.
まあどんなに遅くても年内だそうです。
Well, it'll be by the end of the year at the latest.
パソコン購入予定の方は、ぜひね、今は一旦待ってこちらの購入を検討していただけないでしょうか！
If you're planning to buy a PC, please wait for a moment and consider purchasing this one!
ということでね、楽しみが盛りだくさんです！
So, there's a lot to look forward to!
これからも宝鐘マリンをよろしくお願いします！
Please continue to support Houshou Marine!
出航！
Departure!
宝鐘マリン 生誕祭ライブ / 重大発表あり！ ゲスト多数！
Houshou Marine Birthday Live / Major Announcements! Many Guests!